<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[One Hundred and Eighty Days]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-29T23:51:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Yeon]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gerber File Merging and Packaging (day 3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/29/gerber-file-merging-and-packaging-day-3/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-29T23:37:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/29/gerber-file-merging-and-packaging-day-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really envy programmers. As in, professional programmers who make it their career. They have huge amounts of power at their fingertips and there is a mind-boggling variety of problem domains to work in. And their work is fractally interesting and challenging; anywhere you look, at any level, there are problems to be solved and improvements to be made.</p>

<p>More than all that, though, I envy programmers because they get to make their own tools. They are very similar to a blacksmith from another time. Pretty near any tool a blacksmith would need could be made using a blacksmith&rsquo;s skills. Programmers may be the only modern professionals who, by virtue of the skills they need to carry out their profession, are in the perfect situation to create their own tools.</p>

<p>I think of this whenever I use my EDA tools. They feel so clunky when I can&rsquo;t write quick scripts (never mind using a pre-processor or DSLs) to interact with them. It infuriates me when there&rsquo;s no way to do something other than click through a bunch of dialogs. And it&rsquo;s absolutely ridiculous that there is no effort made to store designs in a format that can be easily read by a human, or at least run through <code>diff</code> to get a feel for what&rsquo;s been changed at a glance.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll gladly rant all day about this, but seeing as I&rsquo;m right up against my deadline, I&rsquo;ll just link to <a href="https://github.com/patrickyeon/edahelp">today&rsquo;s release</a>, which consists of a script to package and merge fabrication outputs from Altium Designer that I started when I finally got fed up with doing it by hand. The old method was to rename layers by hand, generate the output, rename some file extensions by hand, selectively add some files to a .zip file, and upload it to a board shop. Now everything up until the upload is automatic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[kickding.py (day 2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/28/kickding-dot-py-day-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-28T22:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/28/kickding-dot-py-day-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A smaller release today: Romotive ran a kickstarter campaign for our then-new Romo Gen3 product. At the time we were all working, eating, and hanging out in a couple apartments in the Ogden (contrary to some of the press, there were more apartments than just those two so that we could get a bit of personal space, and bedrooms). I quickly threw together <a href="https://github.com/patrickyeon/kickding">kickding.py</a> to give out a little Romo &ldquo;Yay!&rdquo; every time we got a new backer at a tier that earned them a robot.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve never scraped a web page before, just know that <a href="http://www.crummy.com/software/BeautifulSoup/">BeautifulSoup</a> is your best friend. I&rsquo;ve done a few projects that required scraping, and it has been a godsend whether throwing together something quick like this or getting a lot more data out of a web site for a heavier project.</p>

<p>Hopefully some day data will be more readily available through APIs or at least more machine-readable sources. I do often find myself wishing there was an easy way to access the data source backing some documents, and I fear there will be much more scraping and data extraction in my future. At least if I start releasing the tools, even the simple hacks, I write for this, I can hope to save somebody else the trouble down the line.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[INA3221 Library (day 1)]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/27/ina3221-library-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-27T20:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/27/ina3221-library-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As promised, my first release is up at <a href="http://github.com/patrickyeon/arduinolibs/">http://github.com/patrickyeon/arduinolibs/</a>. It&rsquo;s a library for working with <a href="http://www.ti.com/product/ina3221">TI&rsquo;s INA3221</a> current and voltage measurent IC, a chip that I&rsquo;ve been pretty happy with so far, even if it acted a weirdly in our intern&rsquo;s project (I think the problem arose from having current sense resistors, and their measurement channels, in series). His project is the third internal board we&rsquo;ve got this puppy on <a href="http://romotive.com">at work</a>, and I&rsquo;ll probably keep on slapping them down whenever I need a quick-and-easy current measurement.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/27/starting/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-27T18:45:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/27/starting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>180 Releases, 180 Days. Getting started.</h2>

<p>Jennifer Dewalt is <a href="http://blog.jenniferdewalt.com/post/56319597560/im-learning-to-code-by-building-180-websites-in-180">building 180 websites in 180 days</a>, and absolutely killing it. Derek Sivers has a <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6097663">good comment</a> on producing work as an artist on the related Hacker News page. It&rsquo;s a recurring theme in Sivers&#8217; blog posts: you need to get out and ship. Seth Godin says it a lot too: &ldquo;Real artists ship&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Jennifer&rsquo;s powering away on that by blocking off 10 hours a day to produce a new idea and learn everything it takes her to pull it off. I won&rsquo;t commit to 10 hours a day, but I <em>do</em> want to do something similar. So here&rsquo;s my version:</p>

<p>One hundred and eighty days. One release a day. No days off.</p>

<p>A &ldquo;release&rdquo; is a completely subjective measurement, I&rsquo;ll just say &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll know it when I see it&rdquo;. I&rsquo;m not promising to create something new each day, in fact my initial drive is to ship a number of small projects I&rsquo;ve dicked around with and keep on telling myself &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll just clean this up later and then put it online&rdquo;. But any release will be something I haven&rsquo;t put out there before. I&rsquo;m making my own set of rules:</p>

<ul>
<li>Every release is available for free (as in beer) and linked to with a blog post. (Furthermore, I expect the majority of my stuff will be released under a free software or creative commons-like license.)</li>
<li>Every release will be the product of some respectable amount of work. One-liners, simple photos, and quickly-written posts are not enough.</li>
<li>If I don&rsquo;t release something and publish a blog post between 12:01 AM and 11:59 PM (PST), that day&rsquo;s missed and I start over at day 1.</li>
<li>I can quit when I&rsquo;ve successfully hit 180 days in a row.</li>
</ul>


<p>These rules are more flexible than Jennifer&rsquo;s and I&rsquo;m not restricting myself to one medium, but again she&rsquo;s beasting through this and I&rsquo;m just trying to spur myself into a little more action. I trust that I&rsquo;ll be hard enough on myself to keep the bar high enough and not phone it in any days just to keep a streak going.</p>

<p>Today is day one. This is not the first release, but the next post will be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
