<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: meta | One Hundred and Eighty Days]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/categories/meta/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-11T23:29:27-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Yeon]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whoops]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/09/11/whoops/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-11T22:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/09/11/whoops</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Wherein the ball is thoroughly dropped.</h2>

<p>That was a disappointing little experiment. Only three releases done, and then total radio silence for a month and a half. I thought that I was likely to make it out to about 10 days before I ran out of stuff ready to fire off, but that was horribly optimistic. It doesn&rsquo;t help that as soon as I missed a day, I was ready to really let things slip, and eventually nearly forget about it.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still drawn to the idea of forcing myself to publish, even though I&rsquo;m not at all up to the challenge of 180 days straight of pushing out new content. Not yet, at least. I&rsquo;m going to try coming at it from the other end, starting off with a release once a week. When that level of effort is my new normal, I&rsquo;ll step it up and make myself uncomfortable trying for more frequent releases.</p>

<p>My goal is still the same as when I started: 180 releases, 180 days. I&rsquo;m just accepting that there&rsquo;s a longer road to take to get there than I was hoping for at first. I think the underlying drive is still the same; I want to push myself to be more productive than I currently am. I feel like I have a large amount of potential that I am squandering.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/27/starting/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-27T18:45:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/27/starting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>180 Releases, 180 Days. Getting started.</h2>

<p>Jennifer Dewalt is <a href="http://blog.jenniferdewalt.com/post/56319597560/im-learning-to-code-by-building-180-websites-in-180">building 180 websites in 180 days</a>, and absolutely killing it. Derek Sivers has a <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6097663">good comment</a> on producing work as an artist on the related Hacker News page. It&rsquo;s a recurring theme in Sivers' blog posts: you need to get out and ship. Seth Godin says it a lot too: &ldquo;Real artists ship&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Jennifer&rsquo;s powering away on that by blocking off 10 hours a day to produce a new idea and learn everything it takes her to pull it off. I won&rsquo;t commit to 10 hours a day, but I <em>do</em> want to do something similar. So here&rsquo;s my version:</p>

<p>One hundred and eighty days. One release a day. No days off.</p>

<p>A &ldquo;release&rdquo; is a completely subjective measurement, I&rsquo;ll just say &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll know it when I see it&rdquo;. I&rsquo;m not promising to create something new each day, in fact my initial drive is to ship a number of small projects I&rsquo;ve dicked around with and keep on telling myself &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll just clean this up later and then put it online&rdquo;. But any release will be something I haven&rsquo;t put out there before. I&rsquo;m making my own set of rules:</p>

<ul>
<li>Every release is available for free (as in beer) and linked to with a blog post. (Furthermore, I expect the majority of my stuff will be released under a free software or creative commons-like license.)</li>
<li>Every release will be the product of some respectable amount of work. One-liners, simple photos, and quickly-written posts are not enough.</li>
<li>If I don&rsquo;t release something and publish a blog post between 12:01 AM and 11:59 PM (PST), that day&rsquo;s missed and I start over at day 1.</li>
<li>I can quit when I&rsquo;ve successfully hit 180 days in a row.</li>
</ul>


<p>These rules are more flexible than Jennifer&rsquo;s and I&rsquo;m not restricting myself to one medium, but again she&rsquo;s beasting through this and I&rsquo;m just trying to spur myself into a little more action. I trust that I&rsquo;ll be hard enough on myself to keep the bar high enough and not phone it in any days just to keep a streak going.</p>

<p>Today is day one. This is not the first release, but the next post will be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
