<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: electronics | One Hundred and Eighty Days]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/categories/electronics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-11T23:29:27-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Yeon]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gerber File Merging and Packaging (day 3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/29/gerber-file-merging-and-packaging-day-3/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-29T23:37:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrickyeon.github.io/one-eighty-days/blog/2013/07/29/gerber-file-merging-and-packaging-day-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really envy programmers. As in, professional programmers who make it their career. They have huge amounts of power at their fingertips and there is a mind-boggling variety of problem domains to work in. And their work is fractally interesting and challenging; anywhere you look, at any level, there are problems to be solved and improvements to be made.</p>

<p>More than all that, though, I envy programmers because they get to make their own tools. They are very similar to a blacksmith from another time. Pretty near any tool a blacksmith would need could be made using a blacksmith&rsquo;s skills. Programmers may be the only modern professionals who, by virtue of the skills they need to carry out their profession, are in the perfect situation to create their own tools.</p>

<p>I think of this whenever I use my EDA tools. They feel so clunky when I can&rsquo;t write quick scripts (never mind using a pre-processor or DSLs) to interact with them. It infuriates me when there&rsquo;s no way to do something other than click through a bunch of dialogs. And it&rsquo;s absolutely ridiculous that there is no effort made to store designs in a format that can be easily read by a human, or at least run through <code>diff</code> to get a feel for what&rsquo;s been changed at a glance.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll gladly rant all day about this, but seeing as I&rsquo;m right up against my deadline, I&rsquo;ll just link to <a href="https://github.com/patrickyeon/edahelp">today&rsquo;s release</a>, which consists of a script to package and merge fabrication outputs from Altium Designer that I started when I finally got fed up with doing it by hand. The old method was to rename layers by hand, generate the output, rename some file extensions by hand, selectively add some files to a .zip file, and upload it to a board shop. Now everything up until the upload is automatic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
